# Thijs Broerse

TyZ - Think. Yield. Zenith.

Interim Tech Lead / Freelance Senior Frontend Architect
Leusden - the Netherlands / +31 (0) 6 899 36 821 / thijs@tyz.nl / www.tyz.nl

Highly skilled Frontend expert with 20+ years of experience in web development and leadership. Able to set up, develop and maintain complex (frontend) systems, leading (international) development teams.

Worked on many (award winning) projects, specialized in scripting and architecture.



# Expertise

- Complex (Single Page) Applications (SPA) & Progressive Web Apps (PWA)
- Techniques:
  - JavaScript
  - TypeScript
  - React (Redux, Mobx)
  - o Vue
  - Angular
  - o Scripted animations using Canvas, WebGL, Lottie, GSAP, SVG, CSS, etc.
  - o Advanced data handling using GraphQL, Rest API, etc.
  - Accessibility (ally) & internationalization (il8n) expert
- Roles:
  - **Frontend Director** Be responsible for the performance of the whole Frontend team, performance reviews, recruitment, job interviews, career paths
  - Technical Director Leading projects from a technical perspective, set up frameworks and libraries, coding standards, GIT flow, code linters
  - o Architect Set up complex development systems, define API's
  - Lead Developer Providing technical guidance and mentorship to a team of frontend developers
- International experience:
  - Lived 2 years in **Buenos Aires** (Argentina) from 2018 to 2020 to build up a Frontend team from 8 to 30 developers
  - o In 2021 remotely build up a team of 10 developers in **Kazakhstan**
  - o In 2021 remotely build up a team of 4 developers in India

# Work Experience

# **TyZ** - 2023

#### • Interim Tech Lead & Freelance Senior Frontend Architect

- Elevate company development teams through strategic guidance, fostering innovation, and optimizing processes for success.
- o Develop complex web applications

#### MediaMonks - 2008-2023

- Global Frontend Director 2019-2023
  - Lead an international Frontend team with over 140 developers, based in multiple countries (e.g. the Netherlands, Argentina, Kazakhstan, India)
  - + all Frontend Team Lead tasks
- Technical Director 2021-2023
  - o Being technically responsible for all projects for a single client
  - Project estimations
  - Operations
- Frontend Team Lead 2014-2019
  - Created MediaMonks Coding Standards
  - Recruitment and job interviews
  - Performance reviews and career paths
  - o Git Flow and code reviews
  - Architecture
  - Frontend development
- Flash Team Lead, Flash Architect, Senior Flash Developer 2008 2014
  - o Founder & Lead developer of open source project <u>Temple Library</u>
- Part of the MMMT 2011 2019
  - MediaMonks Management Team consisting of 13 Senior Managers

#### Donder Interactive Media - 2008-2014

• Owner / Senior Flash Developer

Flash ActionScript

## Lost Boys - 2006-2008

• Senior Flash Developer

Flash ActionScript

• Maintenance Engineer

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, .NET, Java, Flash ActionScript

# Treshold Automatisering - 2003-2006

• Web Developer

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python, MySQL

## Education

- HKU (Hogeschool voor de Kunsten Utrecht) / University of Portsmouth 2002-2003
   Master of Arts (MA), Interaction Design
- Saxion University of Applied Sciences 1999-2003 Bachelor Kunst & Techniek (Arts & Technique)

# Languages

Dutch native
English fluent
Spanish beginner
German beginner

## Other

Nationality: Dutch
Marital status: Married
Age: 42
Driving license: B

Sports: CrossFit, (obstacle) running, fitness, boxing

Hobbies: Family (dad of 3 beautiful children), cooking, reading, festivals, DJ

## Contact.

Phone: +31 (0) 6 899 36 821

Email: <a href="mailto:thijs@tyz.nl">thijs@tyz.nl</a>
Website: <a href="mailto:http://www.tyz.nl">http://www.tyz.nl</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyz81/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyz81/</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/ThijsTyZ">https://github.com/ThijsTyZ</a>
NPM: <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/~thi.js">https://www.npmjs.com/~thi.js</a>

Codepen: <a href="https://codepen.io/\_TyZ\_">https://codepen.io/\_TyZ\_</a>

## Core values

• Passion deep enthusiasm and dedication.

Reliability consistent dependability and trustworthiness.Sociability valuing meaningful connections with others

• Authenticity embracing and expressing true self

# Project highlights

• **Prologis Operation Essentials** - MediaMonks - 2019

Progressive web app for property managers to contact vendors.

Technique: React, TypeScript, AWS Amplify, AppSync, GraphQL

Role: Technical Director and Lead Developer

• MonkAcademy - MediaMonks - 2019

Internal schooling program to train new and junior Frontend developer

Role: Teacher

• **Genesis Car Configurator** - MediaMonks - 2019

3D experience where you can configure your own Genesis car. Watch your car from every angle, look inside the car, turn on the lights, open doors, etc.

https://www.genesis.com/us/en/2021/genesis-g90.html/#/car-configurator/G90

https://thefwa.com/cases/genesiscom

Technique: Vue, WebGL, TypeScript Role: Architect and Lead Developer

• Kodak Moments - MediaMonks - 2017

Online Photo Book, Canvas, Prints, etc. creator

https://www.kodakmoments.com/

Technique: TypeScript, React with custom server side rendering

Role: Lead Developer

• Efteling - Persoonlijk Sprookje (Personal Fairy Tale) - MediaMonks - 2012

An interactive fairy tale based on your personal visit to theme park Efteling. The fairy tale can be turned into a real book

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zds7wDwZCy4

Technique: Flash Role: Lead Developer

• Albert Heijn - Voetbalplaatjes campaign (Hyves) - MediaMonks - 2011

Create your own football picture

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Eshbfdn69Ts

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KHCGUziH\_EQ

Technique: Flash Role: Lead Developer

• **Apart Game Table** - HKU graduation project - 2003

A physical game table with 5 rows and 16 columns, 80 parts. Each part is a button and can light up in several colors and allows you to play games.

Technique: Director Lingo, Flash

Role: Game Developer

• **Eastcore** - Self Employed - 2002

A social media platform with chat, photo upload, agenda and much more. Built before Facebook even existed!

Technique: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL

Role: Owner / Web Developer

## References

"During Thijs his 15 years at the Media.Monks he has shown to be a specialist within his role and able to maneuver in a dynamic high paced environment and skilled in communicating with stakeholders across different teams. Next to this he has also invested in improving the company culture and wellbeing through his efforts within the Culture Club. Some traits that add to the above and Thijs has shown throughout his time with Media.Monks are: critical thinking, connectivity, empathy and mentorship."

#### Anne van Zessen - HR Business Partner at MediaMonks

"I've worked with Thijs for 12,5 years and have always been impressed by his skill and knowledge. He's an absolute legend and one of the best I've ever worked with. Would absolutely recommend!"

# Dennis de Rooij - Project Director at MediaMonks

"Thijs is a machine. Not only is he a very skilled developer but he's someone who likes to strive for top quality and transfer his knowledge to everyone in his team. During my years working with him, I not only learned from his technical skills but also from his vast experience leading other developers (which included many highly skilled, experienced programmers)."

## Ronald Méndez - Operations Director at MediaMonks & FWA Jury Member

"I highly recommend Thijs for his great technical skills and ability to deliver high quality work. He possess a friendly and approachable nature, fostering a collaborative work environment. With his attention to detail and commitment to meeting deadlines, he is a valuable asset to any development team."

#### Robert Slootjes - Technical Director at MediaMonks

"Having worked with Thijs over a period of more than 15 years, I can honestly say that Thijs is one of the people I have enjoyed most working with. Thijs is a hard worker, with great dedication and focus, who will always go the extra mile to reach the best result possible. As a developer he has vast knowledge of the field he is active in, always strives for improvements, and puts quality first. He has a broad perspective, always trying to view things from multiple sides, and is always willing to learn new things. As a team lead Thijs takes great care of his team members, putting their interests in favour of his own, while using a personal approach to each and every one to make sure they have an optimal environment to work, thrive and develop in. Besides that, Thijs is generally a really nice guy with a great sense of humour, easy going and flexible, with a strong focus on principles without being dogmatic. Any company should feel proud and blessed to have Thijs in their team."

Stephan Bezoen - Lead Android Developer at MediaMonks

Read more: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyz81/details/recommendations/